Guide to the Chimera Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Chimera papers
1943-1959
YCAL MSS 35
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3
(8 boxes)
The Chimera Papers consist of manuscripts, correspondence, and business papers relating to the publishing history of Chimera: A Literary Journal (1942-1947), with manuscripts of writings by Barbara Howes, editor of Chimera from 1943 to 1947.
Chimera
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Barbara Howes presented Chimera material to Beinecke Library in 1960.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
CHIMERA
Chimera, a "little magazine," was begun in 1942 as a campus publication by several Princeton students, chief among them William Arrowsmith, J. Fearon Brown, and Benjamin Ford, who served as the first editors. After the first issue appeared in Spring, 1942, Frederick Morgan replaced Ford. David Newton, Barbara Howes, and Ximena de Angulo eventually replaced these three, who entered military service. Originally titled Chimera: A Rough Beast (the phrase taken from Yeats), the name was officially changed to Chimera: A Literary Quarterly beginning with the Autumn 1944 issue. With its editorial offices moved to New York City after the first issue, the journal survived until 1947, producing a total of twenty quarterly issues averaging fifty pages each.
In the first issue, the editors claimed that the journal's purpose was "to try to provide a medium for serious writers, with emphasis on the younger ones." A later editorial policy by editor Barbara Howes identified four basic platforms: (1) "to provide an opening for young or unpublished writers, interested in both creative and critical work"; (2) "to encourage writers from other parts of the country"; (3) to "provide American readers with a wider acquaintance with the literary scene in other countries"; and (4) "to print non-technical contributions from philosophy, psychology, and comparative religions, as well as the other arts." In 1945 Howes stated that "the emphasis now is less on presenting younger writers, and more on presenting significant material on a wide cultural basis... ."
From the beginning, the journal was interested in covering a broad spectrum of the humanities: literature, art, philosophy, and psychology. The early issues leaned heavily toward poetry and book reviews; later issues included more fiction and longer critical articles. Two special issues were devoted to myth and to detective fiction.
In its five-year life, Chimera published poetry by John Berryman, Babette Deutsch, Lawrence Durrell, Richard Eberhart, Randall Jarrell, Robert Lowell, Pablo Neruda, Kenneth Patchen, Allen Tate, and others; and articles by W.H. Auden, R.P. Blackmur, Carl Jung, Thomas Mann, Henry Miller, Henri Peyre, Mario Praz, Marguerite Yourcenar, and others. The journal also published previously untranslated works by Rimbaud, Sartre, Corbière, and Moravia.
Chimera was widely praised for its pleasing design and typography (by Van Vechten Press of Metuchen, New Jersey). Malcolm Cowley in The New Republic called it "the handsomest of all the little magazines; it is the only one that tries to rival the fine French reviews." In a 1944 Saturday Review article, William Rose Benét applauded Chimera for its articles on significant European authors who were little known in the U.S., and Lawrence Durrell called the journal "the best of the American literary papers."
Primarily because of financial difficulties the journal ceased publication after the Summer, l947 issue.
Scope and Contents
The Chimera papers document the publishing activities of a New York based "little magazine" between its inception in 1942 and its cessation in 1947. The papers span the years between 1943 and 195l, with the bulk covering the years of Barbara Howes's editorship, 1943-1947.
Housed in eight boxes, the collection is divided into three series: I. Correspondence; II. Business Papers; and III. Manuscript Submissions
Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by author in Boxes 1-2. The correspondence covers the years 1943-1947 and includes notes and letters from notable authors and critics such as Jacques Barzun, R. P. Blackmur, Malcolm Cowley, Lawrence Durrell, Richard Eberhart, Wallace Fowlie, Randall Jarrell, Thomas Mann, Henry Miller, Marianne Moore, George Orwell, Henri Peyre, Dorothy Sayers, Wallace Stevens, Allen Tate, and Lionel Trilling. The letters are generally short and often discuss routine business matters such as subscriptions or manuscripts submitted to Chimera; many offer advice or praise.
More substantive letters are scattered throughout the collection. C. G. Wallis writes a lengthy letter-essay on June 15, 1943 on Philip Wheelwright and Kenneth Burke's positions on metaphysics and "knowing" in science and theology; in a letter of July 4, 1945 Louise Bogan discusses the esoteric in literature; and Henry Miller makes a plea for financial help for author-traveler George Dibbern. A letter from Edwin Seldon (Box 2, folder 75) discusses the poetry of Éluard; Francis Fergusson discusses the works of Paul Claudel; Enrique de Ezcurra (Box 1, folder 17) comments (in Spanish) on current Spanish literature; and Raymond Cook (Box 1, folder 13) comments on directions in recent Southern literature. Maria Jolas's letters refer to problems in translating Sartre.
First-hand accounts of conditions in post-war Europe can be found in letters from Elmer Diktonius (Box 1, folder 18), Allanah Harper, Lawrence Durrell, and Olivia Manning. Analyses of various characteristics and themes of detective fiction may be found in the letters of Alan Harrington (Box 1, folder 31), G. Robert Stange, Philip Van Doren Stern, and Hugh Wheeler ("Quentin Patrick") (Box 2, folder 96). Many letters comment on Chimera, but see especially those of Sherman Conrad (Box 1, folder 13), James Boyer May, John Nerber, Hardiman Scott (Box 2, folder 75), and John Stewart. Several letters by G. W. Van Vechten of Van Vechten Press discuss publication layouts, and letters to and from Chimera editors William Arrowsmith, David Newton, Fearon J. Brown, Frederick Morgan, and Ximena de Angulo reveal much about the editorial practices and problems of the journal.
Series II, Business Papers, is chronologically arranged in Boxes 3-6 and covers such areas as advertising and promotions, editorial papers, finances, invoices, printed material, and subscription papers.
Advertising and Promotions contain promotional correspondence with bookstores, libraries, newspapers, etc.; samples of promotional material from Chimera and other literary journals; and letters and order forms concerning advertising in Chimera and Chimera 's advertising in other journals. Editorial Papers include editor's plans for contents and layouts of individual issues, a copy of Chimera 's editorial policy by Barbara Howes (June, 1945), information on the significance of the journal's title and references to chimeras in literature, three newspaper articles on detective fiction, and a list of proof symbols used by Chimera editors.
Finances contain financial statements for Chimera, copies of printing bills, letters relating to financing, and a receipt book listing payments to contributors, 1946-1948. Invoices hold copies of invoices sent by Chimera to subscribers and consignees between 1943 and 1951. Printed Material contains copies of newspaper and magazine articles making reference to Chimera and "little magazines" in general, along with a brief biographical sketch of Barbara Howes. Subscription Papers cover the years 1942-1951 and contain lists of current and potential subscribers, purchase orders, and bills for subscriptions.
Series III, Manuscript Submissions (Boxes 7-8), contains typed copies of most of the poems, articles, stories, and reviews appearing in Chimera between Autumn, 1943 and Summer, 1947, most of them with corrections and suggested changes, presumably by Barbara Howes. Included also are some final page proofs for accepted contributions. The series concludes with two folders of manuscripts intended for future publication. Among the submissions in this series are poems by John Berryman, Babette Deutsch, Richard Eberhart, Pablo Neruda, Kenneth Patchen, and Peter Viereck; articles by Jacques Barzun, Louise Bogan, Hermann Broch, Kenneth Burke, Wallace Fowlie, C. G. Jung, Mario Praz, Paul Rosenfeld, Jean Wahl, and Marguerite Yourcenar; and stories by Alex Comfort and Philip Van Doren Stern. Brief biographical sketches are included for most of the authors. There is also some correspondence between editor and contributors relating to manuscript changes.
Chimera; American literature -- Periodicals; Authors and publishers -- United States; Fiction; Little magazines; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Poetry; Publishers and publishing -- United States; Authors; Poets; Arrowsmith, William, 1924-1992; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-2012; Bogan, Louise, 1897-1970; Broch, Hermann, 1886-1951; Comfort, Alex, 1920-2000; Durrell, Lawrence, 1912-1990; Eberhart, Richard, 1904-2005; English, Maurice; Fowles, Wallace, 1908-; Howes, Barbara, 1914-1996; Jolas, M.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980; Peyre, Henri, 1901-1988; Praz, Mario, 1896-1982; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946; Stern, Philip Van Doren, 1900-1984; Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955; Swallow, Alan, 1915-1966; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979; Troy, William, 1903-1961; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006; Yourcenar, Marguerite, 1903-1987
- Correspondence, 1943-1947; Series I; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by author and then chronologically, with undated correspondence placed at the end of each author's file. Separate folders have been established for correspondents with three or more items. Correspondents for whom there are fewer than three items have been placed in "Letter" general files.
  - "A" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arrowsmith, William, 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "B" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Becker, Edwin J., 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bentley, Eric, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blackmur, R. P., 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bogan, Louise, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brickell, Herschel, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Broch, Hermann, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Fearon J., 1944-45, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "C" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Centaur (Amsterdam), 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Codman, Florence, 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Collins, Maurice, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "D" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - De Angulo, Ximena, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Deming, Barbara, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Durrell, Lawrence, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "E" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Embler, Weller, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - English, Maurice, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "F" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fowlie, Wallace, 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "G" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Graham, W. S., 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "H" general, 1943-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Harper, Allanah, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Harrigan, Anthony, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Hemley, Cecil, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hoppin, Hector, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Horizon, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "J" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Jacobson, Herbert, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Jolas, Maria, 1945, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "K" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Kahler, Erich, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "L" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Laughlin, James, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Loomis, Payson, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "M" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 48-49)
  - Manning, Olivia, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Marshall, Margaret, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - May, James Boyer, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Mellon, Mary, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Mellon, Paul, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Mercier, Vivian, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mespoulet, Marguerite, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Miller, Henry, 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Monteforte, Mario, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Morgan, Frederick, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Morris, Ira V., 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - "N" general, 1944-46, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Neider, Charles, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Nerber, John, 1945-47 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Newton, David, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "O" general, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - "P" general, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Patrick, Quentin
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Hugh Wheeler, Box 2, folder 96
  - Peyre, Henri, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Poggioli, Renato, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Praz, Mario, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - "R" general, 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Robertson, Priscilla, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Roditi, Edouard, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Roskolenko, Harry, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "S" general, 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 75-76)
  - Shapiro, Meyer, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Shurtleff, Michael, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Sjögren, Erik, 1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Stallman, Robert, 1945-47 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Stange, G. Robert, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Stevens, Wallace, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Stewart, John L., 1944-46 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Stiles, George, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Swallow, Alan (Swallow Press), 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Sylvestre, Guy, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - "T" general, 1943-47 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Tate, Allen, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Troy, William, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - "U" general, 1944-46 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1944-46 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - "V" general, 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Van Vechten, G.W. (Van Vechten Press), 1944-47, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1945-47 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - "W" general, 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Waggoner, Hyatt H., 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Wahl, Jean, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Winston, Richard, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - "Y" general, 1944-47 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Yourcenar, Marguerite, 1945-47 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - "Z" general, 1947, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Unidentified, 1944-46 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Correspondence: chronological list (Box 2, Folder 104)
- Business Papers, 1942-51; Series II; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series II, Business Papers, is subdivided into ten alphabetically arranged subject files and organized chronologically within each file.
  - Advertising and promotions, 1943-47 (Box 3, Folder 105-08)
  - Consignments to Bob DeBoer (agent), 1944-47 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Copyright permissions, 1943-48 (Box 3, Folder 110-11)
  - Copyright registrations, 1943-47 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Editorial papers, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Finances, 1944-48 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Invoices, 1943-51 (Box 4, Folder 115-32a)
  - Poster artwork mechanical, ca. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 132b)
  - Posters, 1944-47 (Box 4, Folder 132c)
  - Printed material, 1944-46, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Subscription lists, 1944, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Subscription correspondence and papers, 1942-45 (Box 5, Folder 135-52)
  - Subscription correspondence and papers, 1946-51 (Box 6, Folder 153-71)
- Manuscript Submissions, 1943-47; Series III; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Manuscript Submissions, is grouped chronologically by issue. Within each file the arrangement is alphabetical by author, with miscellaneous material placed at the end.
  - Submissions to Vol. II, No. 1, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    Includes: "Cicero" by Osmond Beckwith; "Tactics of Motivation" by Kenneth Burke (corrected); "The Martyrdom of the House" by Alexander Comfort; "Iowa City Zoo" by Jean Garrigue (corrected); "Street Songs" by Edith Sitwell; "The Swan" by Howard Moss; Review of Brooks Adams' The Law of Civilization and Decay by Stow Persons; Review of Klaus Mann's Andre Gide and the Crisis of Modern Thought by Henri Peyre; "The Vaudeville Year" by Coleman Rosenberger.
  - Submissions to Vol. II, No. 2, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    Includes: "The Adventure of Sara Drabble and the Green Bird" by Margaret Currier Boylen; Review of Alfred Kazin's On Native Grounds by Kenneth Burke; Review of Oscar Williams' The Book of New Poems: 1943 by Reuel Denney; "Carapace" by Babette Deutsch; "Tryptych" by Richard Eberhart; "The Juggler's Dance: a note on Crane and Rimbaud" by Wallace Fowlie; "Girl At Midnight" by Weldon Kees; Review of Karl Jay Shapiro's Person Place and Thing by Arthur Mizener; "The Age of Pericles" by Kenneth Patchen.
  - Submissions to Vol. II, No. 3, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    Includes: "Script" by Beverly Baff; "The Acrobats" by John Malcolm Brinnin; Review of Merle Curti's The Growth of American Thought by H.A. Brinser; "Watch" by Priscilla Bromley; "Annunciation" by Harvey Buchanan; "Harbor Impression" by Gray Burr; "White Lily and Hail" by Richard Eberhart; "Ballads for Janus" by Ewin Honig; "Carpe Diem" by Barbara Howes; "Interlude with a Pu-Pu Bird" by Nicholas Moore; Review of Dunstan Thompson's Poems by Howard Moss; "The Robbery" by Howard Moss; "Major Catastrophe" by David Newton;"Amour Among Animals" by Emma Swan;"The New Parnassianism and Recent Poetry" by William Troy (two versions: corrected and uncorrected); "On Poetry" by Jean Wahl.
  - Submissions to Vol. II, No. 4, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 175)
    Includes: Review of Robert Penn Warren's Selected Poems 1923 -1943 by William Arrowsmith; Phoenices by Herbert Cahoon; "The Portable Forge" by Alex Comfort; Review of VVV No. 4 by Dorothy Dudley (corrected, with letter); "The Poetic Tradition of St. John Perse" by Wallace Fowlie; "Fair-Day" by John Maher Murphy; Translation of Arthur Rimbaud's "The Desserts of Love" by Louise Varese; Translation of Arthur Rimbaud's Five Prose Poems by Louise Varese.
  - Submissions to Vol. III, No. 1, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    Includes: "In Memoriam: R.H.P., 1907-1944" by Jacques Barzun (corrected); "Calamity", "Voyage Autour De Ma Chambre", and "Naushon" by Robert Pitney; "Compassionata At Hyde Park Corner" by Sybille Bedford; "Lynx" by R. A. D. Ford; "At The Seashore" by Ruth Herschberger; "The Birth of a Myth" by Arthur Koestler; Review of Wallace Fowlie's "Clowns and Angels" by Henry Miller; Translation of Henri Peyre's Paul Claudel by Harvey Buchanan.
  - Submissions to Vol. III, No. 2, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    Includes: "Warning to a Foetus" by Ted Bootum; Review of Maurice Collis' The Land of The Great Image by Mary Evelyn Clarke; "An Old Arakanese Love Poem" by Maurice Collis; "Exposition Of A Method" by Barbara Deming.
  - Submissions to Vol. III, No. 2, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    Includes: "Exposition Of A Method" by Maurice Collis; Review of Sir Osbert Sitwell's Right Hand, Left Hand by Allanah Harper; "In The Snow-World" by Robert Horan; "Poem" by Joan Murray.
  - Submissions to Vol. III, No. 3, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    Includes: Translation of Louis Bertrand's Gaspard De La Nuit by William Troy; Translation of Alexander Blok's "My Friend's Life" by Gareth Endor; "Exposition Of A Method" by Barbara Deming (corrected); "The Death Of Virgil" by Paul Rosenfeld (corrected); "The Appointed Hour" by Philip Van Doren Stern.
  - Submissions to Vol. III, No. 4, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    Includes: "Travelling South" by John Berryman; "The Other Landscape" by Fredrika Blair; "Flight Of The Children" by Cecil Hemley; "Le Mur" by Jean-Paul Sartre; "The Wall" by Jean-Paul Sartre; "New Guinea, 1944" by Roger Shattuch; "The Day's No Rounder Than Its Angles Are" by Peter Viereck; "Love Poem" by Peter Viereck; "Notes on the Uses of Coincidence in the Novels of E.M. Forster" by Hyatt Howe Waggoner.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 1, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    Includes: "The Odyssey Of Con- temporary Spanish Poetry" by Bernardo Clariana (corrected); Translation of Denis de Rougemont's Dream and Mystique by Maria Jolas; "F. Scott Fitzgerald and the Future" by Weller Embler; "Fooled In Sleep" by Robert Horan; Translation of Carlos Montenegro's "The Ring" by Helen B. Macmillan; "The Converse Tree" by Robert Stallman; "Deborah's Wheel" by Joan Strong; "Identical Mirrors Placed Opposite Each Other In A Hall" by Emman Swan.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 2, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    Includes: "A Change of Tense" by Anthony Harrigan;"Bread and Circuses" by Herbert Jacobson; Correspondence between Barbara Howes and Herbert Jacobson; "An Edwardian Satirist" by John Jamieson; "Les Pas Dans L'Escalier" by Tamara Loundine with a translation by Louise Varese; "After The Night Office," "Fugitive" and "The Ohio River" by Thomas Merton; "Letters In Exile" by John Nerber.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 2, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    Includes: "The Art Of Wilde's Criticism" by Edouard Roditi (Corrected); "In The Circle Of The Family" by George Stiles.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 3, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    Includes: "Myths For Materialists" by Jacques Barzun; "The Secular Hell" by Louise Bogan; "The Mythic Heritage Of Poetry" by Hermann Broch (Corrected); "Myth and Initiation" by Nicolas Calas (Corrected); "Finnegan The Wake" by Joseph Campbell.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 3, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    Includes: translation of Erich Kahler's "The Persistence of Myth" by Eleanor Wolff; "Old Myths Of The New World" by Mario Monteforte-Toledo; "Postlude: Myth, Method, and the Future" by William Troy; " Two Greek Myths In Palladian Perspectives" by Marguerite Yourcenar.
  - Submissions to Vol. IV, No. 4, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    Includes: "The Importance Of B. Traven" by H.R. Hays; translation of Tristan Corbiere's "Nightingale Of The Mud" by Walter McElroy; "The Boy With The Dreamy Eyes" by Michael Shurtleff; "Three Greek Myths In Palladian Perspective" by Marguerite Yourcenar.
  - Submissions to Vol. V, No. 1, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    Includes: "Truth Of History - History Of Truth" by Stanley Dell; review of Eric Bentley's The Paywright As Thinker by Barbara Deming; review of George Orwell's Animal Farm by Maurice English; "Delta Cycle: A Study Of William Faulkner" by James T. Jackson; "A Spot Of Leave" by Olivia Manning; "Spain In The Heart" by Pablo Neruda; "Sonnet" by Emily Mosser Tompkins.
  - Submissions to Vol. V, No. 2, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 188)
    Includes: "Eternal Contemporaries" by Lawrence Durrell; review of Federico Garcia Lorca's La Casa De Bernarda Alba by Francis Fergusson; "The Magician Of The Air" by Anthony Harrigan; review of Thomas Merton's A Man In The Divided Sea by Walter McElroy; a dialogue between Thomas Mann and Karl Kerenyi (corrected); "The Italian Literary Scene Of Today" by Mario Praz; "New England Autumn" by Lewis Spence; "A Short Way by Rail" by George Stiles; "Rats!: Behavior among Behaviorists" by Inez Thrift.
  - Submissions to Vol. V, No. 3, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    Includes: "The Eranos Conferences" by J. M. Hondius; "Individual and Mass Psychology" by C. G. Jung; "Vision and Revision" by W. R. Johnson; "Sonnet" by Emily Mosser Tompkins; "Austin Clarke: The Poet In The Theatre" by Vivian Mercier; "Holy Fire" by Olivia Manning; "The Island Of Dreams" by Alberto Moravia.
  - Submissions to Vol. V, No. 3, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    Includes: "Contemporary Literature: Sweden" by Erik Sjogren (corrected); "The Peacock Of Java" by William Jay Smith; "Terence Died" by Joan Strong.
  - Submissions to Vol. V, No. 4, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 191)